Hello,
I'm here to help you report a workplace concern.
Please note that this call is being recorded for documentation purposes.
All information shared will remain confidential,
and you can choose to remain completely anonymous if you prefer.
Sharing your name is entirely optional.
Can you tell me what happened? Hello,
I need to report a problem at work. Last week my manager called me
into his office, Told me to pack my things and leave immediately.
No warning. No explanation. I have a family of was my only income.
I don't know what I did wrong. I understand this must be very concerning
for you, especially with a family to support.
Can you tell me more about what happened in that meeting?
Did your manager say anything at all about why you were being let go?
Or was there any paperwork involved? Thank you for understanding.
In that meeting he just said, take your bag and hand in your card.
You're done today. No reason. I asked why and he said decision from above.
There was no letter, no warning, nothing to sign.
Security walked me out after I turned in my badge.
That sounds incredibly stressful. Being given no explanation,
especially without any paperwork or warning,
is concerning. How long had you been working there and had you received any
complaints or disciplinary actions before this happened?
I've been there just over three years. Started as a general worker and moved
to the crushing plant crew. I've never had a warning,
no written or verbal. My supervisor even praised me last month for covering extra
night shifts. Three years is a significant amount of time to be employed somewhere.
It makes this even more troubling that you had no warnings and were recently
praised for your work. Can you tell me the specific date this happened and
which company or facility this was at? It happened last week,
on November 7th, 2025.
I work at the Mavita Minerals crushing plant near Moatai's Ted Province.
The contractor on my contract is Zanbazi Site Services.
Thank you for providing those details. I've noted the exact date,
location, and contractor information from your report.
Can you tell me who else was present during this meeting besides your manager,
and do you know if any of your coworkers witnessed what happened or have
experienced similar treatment? It
was just me and my manager, Sr. Alberto.
After he called security, two guards came to the door and walked me out.
On the floor, a couple of guys from my shift saw me being escorted,
Joaquim and Mateus, but they didn't hear the conversation.
About similar treatment, two weeks before,
a welder from maintenance, Orlando,
was also told to go home suddenly. He said they blamed instructions from Maputo,
but he also got no letter. I can share their numbers if needed.
Thank you for sharing that information about Joachim and Matthias witnessing the event.
It's significant that Orlando had a similar experience recently.
This helps us understand if there's a pattern.
Before we discuss contact information,
I want to remind you that sharing your own name and contact details is
entirely optional. You can remain completely anonymous if you prefer.
Would you be comfortable sharing how we might contact you for follow-up,
or would you prefer to keep this report anonymous?
I can share my details, that's okay.
My name is Ernesto Niacole. Phone is 843-729-152.
I'm staying in Matundo near Tete Town.
If you need co-workers' contacts too, I can provide them.
Thank you for sharing your name and contact information,
Ernesto. Can you spell your name for me letter by letter so I can
make sure I have it recorded correctly? Sure.
E-R-N-E-S-T-O.
Space. N-H-A-C-A-A-E.
Thank you for spelling that out, Ernesto.
I've noted your name and contact information down below in our system.
Before we finish, I want to make sure I have everything clear.
You mentioned you worked at the crushing plant.
What type of work were you doing there specifically?
And were you paid hourly or hourly? Thank you.
I was on a crushing plant
operations crew, monitoring the feeders and conveyors,
clearing blockages, doing basic greasing and housekeeping,
and assisting during shutdowns. I'm on a monthly salary with overtime when we do
night shifts. Thank you for clarifying the details about your role and compensation
structure. Based on everything you've shared,
this appears to be an urgent matter since you've already lost your income with
no clear justification. Is there anything else important about this situation
that you'd like to add to the report? Yes. My access card and last
week's overtime weren't paid, and HR hasn't given me a termination letter
or reason despite my calls. I'm asking to be reinstated,
or if they're letting me go, to get proper notice pay,
accrued leave, and a fair retrenchment package.
I can send screenshots of my call logs and pay slips if needed.
Thank you for providing those additional details. I
understand how frustrating this must be,
especially with unpaid overtime and no proper documentation.
This is important information that strengthens your case.
I have all the details recorded, your sudden dismissal on November 7th with no
explanation or paperwork, the unpaid overtime,
and your request for reinstatement or proper termination compensation.
This report will be reviewed by the appropriate personnel and kept confidential.
Is there anything else you'd like to add?
Thank you for taking this seriously.
Just please note I have two kids and my wife isn't working,
so I'm really under pressure for rent and food this month.
If there's any way to speed up the follow-up or help me get a
letter from HR, I'd appreciate it. And I can share Joaquim,
Mateus, and Orlando's numbers if needed.
I understand the pressure you're under with your family situation.
That financial strain makes this even more urgent,
And I've noted that in your report. The information about Yohannam,
Mateus, and Orlando as witnesses is helpful.
If you're comfortable sharing their contact details,
that would strengthen the case. But it's entirely up to you.
Would you like to provide those numbers now? Yes,
you can add them. Joaquim, 84596-3127.
Mateus, 84403891.
Orlando, 826754103. Thank you for moving this
along. Thank you for providing those additional witness contact information,
Joahim, Mateus, and Orlando.
I recorded all the details of your grievance,
including your sudden dismissal without explanation,
the unpaid overtime, and, lack of termination documentation,
and your family's urgent financial situation.
This confidential report will be reviewed by appropriate personnel who will work to address
your concerns. Thank you for trusting us with this information,
Ernesto, and I truly hope this gets resolved quickly for you and your family.