We'll jump right in, and I'll be in character for the safety scenario.
Absolutely. So here's the situation.
I'm Michael. And basically we've got a safety issue where we're being made to
work at heights without proper harnesses. This has been going on for a couple
months, and we had a near miss the other day.
I've reported it before, but nothing's changed, so I'm bringing it up now because
it's really a serious concern. I'm sorry.
I'm you're experiencing this, Michael. That sounds like a very serious safety concern,
and I'm glad you're speaking up about it. A near miss at height is
definitely something that needs immediate attention.
Can you tell me exactly when this near miss incident happened?
Was it within the last few days? Yeah,
absolutely. It was just a couple of days ago,
so it's really fresh. One of the guys merely slipped,
and if he'd had a harness, it wouldn't have been a big deal.
But since he didn't, it was a close call. And yeah,
it's definitely something that needs immediate attention, because it could happen again any time.
Thank you for sharing. That must have been frightening to witness, and you're absolutely
right that it could happen again. Can you tell me the specific location where
this happened? Which department or area of the worksite,
and if possible, what type of work you were doing at height?
Sure thing. This happened over in the roofing section of the west building.
We were basically up there doing some structural installs,
you know, placing beams and securing panels.
So it's that whole roofing area where we're working at height,
and that's where the near miss happened. I understand.
That sounds like exactly the kind of work where proper safety equipment is critical.
Can you tell me who was involved in this incident,
the worker who had the near miss, any supervisors who were present,
and if there were other witnesses who saw what happened?
Absolutely. So the worker who had the near miss is a guy named Jake.
He's on our team, and he was right there with a few of us.
There weren't any supervisors directly present at the time,
but a couple of other co-workers saw it happen, and we all talked about
it afterward. So yeah, it's definitely something a few of us witnessed,
and we've been concerned about
This is important information, Michael. I can hear how much you and your coach
care. Co-workers care about each other's safety. You mentioned this has been an ongoing
problem for a couple months. Can you help me understand what type of safety
equipment you should have but aren't being provided with?
And have you or anyone else reported this specific issue to management before?
Absolutely. So we definitely should have proper safety harnesses whenever we're working up there
at those heights. That's standard gear that just hasn't been provided consistently.
And yeah, we've raised it to management before, but it's kind of been brushed
aside or just not followed up on. So it's been an ongoing thing,
and we're just trying to get it addressed now before anything worse happens.
Thank you for being so thorough,
Michael. It's clear this is a serious ongoing safety issue that needs immediate
attention. Since you've had the near miss and this has been reported before without
resolution, would you consider this an immediate danger situation that requires
urgent action or more of an ongoing problem that needs to be addressed soon?
I'd definitely call it an immediate danger. I mean,
it's been ongoing for a while, but after that near miss,
it's clear this isn't just a theoretical problem.
really does need urgent action because we're at risk every day that this isn't
fixed. So yes, I'd say it's something that needs to be treated as urgent
right now. I
completely understand, Michael. This is clearly an urgent safety matter that puts
you and your coworkers at immediate risk.
This information is confidential and will be reviewed by appropriate personnel who can take
immediate action. Is there a phone number or email where we can contact you
for any follow-up? Or would you prefer to remain anonymous?
us. Thank
you so much for sharing this with me, Michael.
I've recorded all the details. The immediate safety concern about missing harnesses
in the West Building roofing section, Jake's near-miss a couple days ago,
and your contact information. Your courage in speaking up could prevent a serious injury.
This will be escalated as an urgent safety matter,
and someone will be in touch with you soon at Entembo at example.com.
Mike, absolutely. I want you to know.
Absolutely,
and quick action of Dave Lott. You got it!
You're very welcome. Thanks for looping- You're very welcome.
Glad I could help out, and if you need to run anything else,
just let me know. Thank you.
You're welcome. It recorded it!
It's in the database! Yeehaw!
Hello.
I'm here to help you report a concern at work. Everything we discuss will
be kept confidential. Can you tell me what happened? Of course.
I can. So, I'm Grace, and the problem is that we're being forced to
do 12-hour shifts without getting paid overtime.
It's been going about three months now,
and if we refuse, they threaten to fire us.
So, it's a very complicated situation and I wanted to report this to see
if we can solve it. Thank you
for sharing this with me, Grace. I'm sorry you're going through this difficult situation
without getting paid This is very serious. I hope I understand better.
Can you tell me in which department or specific area of the company this
is happening? Yes,
I can.
This is happening in the security area, where we do the rotation of shifts
in the control station. Basically everyone who works in this sector is facing this
problem. So it's very specific to the company's
This is important information about the security sector.
I understand.
It's really a,
No problem. Let's go ahead.
I'm here to help with any other information you
All right.
No problem.
If you need anything else,
just let
Grace, we are still talking about your separation I need to know when
exactly this started. Can you remember if it was in August,
September, or what was the month when the 12-hour shifts without overtime started?
Yes, of course.
It started around August.
Before that, we had a normal schedule,
Thank you,
Grace. Augusto has
been around for long time.
Now
I need to know who the supervisors or chefs are who are demanding this
job. Can you tell me the names of the people responsible for these decisions?
Yes,
I The supervisor in charge of this is Mr.
Roberto. He's directly responsible for our security studies and he's the one who started
implementing these changes. So, basically,
his name is the main thing you need to know.
Entendiu. O Sr.
Roberto é o supervisor responsável.
Há mais alguém envolvido nestas decisões
sobre os turnos, como outros supervisores ou gerentes,
e existem colegas que possam servir. Sim.
Além do Sr. Roberto, tem também a gerente de operações,
a Dona Marta, que tá ciente disso e não fez nada pra
mudar, estou a ser.
E, com certeza, vários colegas podem confirmar porque todos nós estamos passando pela mesma
coisa. Compreendo,
Grace. Então temos o Sr.
Roberto como supervisor e a gerente de operações também envolvida,
vida. Além de vários colegas como testemunhas.
That a classic. Confirmando que se trata principalmente de um problema de salários.
Turnos de 12 horas sem pagamento de horas extras.
Isso mesmo. Você entendeu perfeitamente. O principal problema é exatamente esse.
Turnos de 12 horas
sem pagamento de horas extras. Então, na questão de salários e de condições de
trabalho
Perfeito,
Grace. Entendi completamente. Vamos registrar isso como problema de horas extras não pagas em
turnos de 12 horas. Muito obrigada por compartilhar e vamos garantir
que isso seja a********. Grace, ainda preciso de mais alguns detalhes para completar o
seu relato. Pode me descrever nas suas próprias palavras exatamente o que acontece quando
vocês são obrigados a fazer estes turnos
de 12 horas. Claro,
posso descrever sim. Basicamente, a gente chega para o nosso túnel normal e eles
nos informam que vamos ter que ficar 12 horas, sem opção de recusar.
Eles dizem que se não aceitarmos, corremos o risco de ser demitidos.
E no final não pagam nada mais por essas horas extras,
então no dia-a-dia a gente fica sobrecarregada
This situation is really unfair, Grace. Thank you for explaining how this daily pressure
Now I need to know. Do you consider this an immediate danger?
A continuous problem that needs to be solved?
Or a general concern that can wait Eu
diria que é um problema contínuo que precisa ser resolvido o quanto antes.
Não é exatamente um perigo imediato,
como um acidente, mas é uma situação injusta que está afetando todo mundo e
realmente precisa de uma solução rápida. Compreendo perfeitamente,
Grace. É um problema contínuo que afeta toda a equipa e precisa de solução
urgente. To conclude, would you like to leave a contact,
phone number or email so we can follow this case?
This is optional and your identity Of
course.
Posso deixar o meu email para acompanhamento,
assim vocês podem entrar em contato se precisarem de mais alguma informação.
Então, podem me contatar em graça e pintam o exemplo arrobaemail.com.
Agradeço muito pela ajuda.
Muito obrigado, Grace. Recebi todas as informações importantes sobre a situação
no setor de segurança com os turnos de 12 horas,
sem pagamento de horas extras. This information is confidential and will
be reviewed by the appropriate staff to find a solution.
I am very grateful for your understanding.
Oh, really? I knew this was going to be reviewed.
Thanks for the support and help in finding a solution for all of us.
You're welcome,
Grace. It was important for you
to talk about this. Situations like this really need
to be reported. We hope this complaint will help solve the problem for the
entire security team. Take good care of yourself.
Thank you very
much for your words and attention.
I am very relieved to know that this will be taken into account. I
will take care it, and I hope that everything will be resolved for everyone.
I am happy to know that you feel more relieved,
Grace. Your courage to speak will make a difference for all of us.
Have a good day,
and remember that we are here if you need anything else. Thank you very
much. I will remember this and thank you from the bottom of my heart
for all the help. Have a
Thank you very much. Yeah.