Hello,
I'm here to help you report a workplace concern.
Everything we discuss will be kept confidential.
Can you tell me what happened? Hello,
I need to report a problem at work. It's about a safety issue at
Construction Site North. We're working at Heights and there are no safety harnesses provided.
I saw a near miss yesterday. One guy slipped on the scaffolding and barely
caught himself. I've told my supervisor three times over the last two months and
nothing's changed. I'm really worried someone's going to fall.
Thank you for telling me. That sounds scary.
And I'm sorry this hasn't been addressed.
Please share your name so we can record it. Could you spell it letter
by letter? Okay,
sure. My name is J-J-O-C-M-A-N.
Could you spell your f- You're welcome. Thank
you. I heard Juliet,
Juliet.