It goes to the foreign contractors. It's really discouraging.
I feel like no matter how hard I work, I'm not considered.
Thank you for sharing this with me, Hannah. I understand how discouraging that must
feel when promotions and training seem unfair.
Your identity can remain anonymous. Yes, it's been, I understand that.
Yes, I understand that. With them,
what happened exactly? Can you describe the situation for me?
It's happening across three main sites,
Matombo, Chibwe, and Maputo.
At our operations center here, the openings get posted.
But when locals apply, they apply, the roles end up filled by foreign contractors
who didn't even meet all the listed requirements.
For example, the shift cord, And it's not just about the shifts.
The training manuals are clear, but when it's time to pick who gets trained,
the local candidates get overlooked. Like last month,
five slots opened for the new crane certification.
Four went to foreign contractors, one to a manager's cousin.
Locals with more hours on the machines weren't even called.
It makes us feel stuck, you know? That sounds incredibly frustrating,
Hannah. It's completely understandable why you'd feel stuck.
Stuck. When your experience isn't being valued like it should be.
Exactly. And it's not just about getting trained.
The pay is different too. For the same roles,
the contractors are getting higher rates and allowances.
I found out when a foreign hire asked me how to file his per
diem. Turns out he gets one,
and we don't. When I raised it with my supervisor in September,
he said that's just how the contracts are.
Can you look into who approved those pay and,
I can share names if needed. I've got the list right here from when
we talked about it last month. But first,
I need to know who makes these decisions at your end.
If you want, I can give you the names of the supervisors and HR
folks tied to those decisions. Also the posting IDs for the August shift coordinator
and the crane training list from last month. What details do you need first?
Thank you for offering to provide those details,
Hannah. That information would be very helpful for our investigation.
Could you spell out the names of those supervisors?
Okay, I'll make a note. Okay,
sure. For Mutombo Site,
Supervisor Maria Ntumwa. That's her name exactly as it appears on the roster.
Chibwe Site, Supervisor Paulo Mbeve.
Maputo Site, Training Coordinator Sergio Almeida.
Operation Center,
HR Officer Lydia Carmo. And for the crane certification list,
Manager Joaquin Nunez. Thank you for providing those names,
Hannah. Maria Ntumwa from Mutombo,
Paulo Mbeve from Maputo, Sergio Almeida at the training center,
Lydia Carmo in HR, and Joaquin Luna as manager of the crane certification
list. This information is confidential and will be reviewed by
appropriate personnel. I understand.
Thank you for taking this seriously, Maria. Before we wrap,
do you need my contact? It's Hana Mautumwa.
I'm usually on the day shift at the office. I can also send copies
of the postings and the training list if that helps.
Yes, I'd appreciate your contact information.
It's helpful to have it on file. Okay, you can reach me at the
operation center. Sure.
You can find me on the roster. Great.
Right. I understand. Okay,
thank you for confirming that. Great.
I appreciate you sharing all this information with me today,
Hannah. Your concerns are valid,
and this information is important. I appreciate
you saying that. I just want things to be fair for all of us
here at the mines, you know? If you need anything else,
let me know. I'm available during day shift.
Thank you for listening, and for keeping this confidential.
I understand completely, Hannah. Your concern for fairness is exactly
why this information matters. And yes,
your confidentiality is absolutely guaranteed.
Thank you, Maria. I appreciate that assurance.
If you need documents, I can drop printed copies at the secur- You're
welcome. I'll be around if you need me. Thank you for taking- Okay.
Thank you for your time today. If you need to reach me,
ask for Hana Matumwa at the Operations Center,
day shift. I can bring the posting IDs and training materials.
Thank you again,
Hannah. We'll be in touch soon about the next steps with your information.
Thank you, Maria. I'll be waiting to hear from you.
If anything changes on my side, I'll update you.
Thanks again for listening today. Thank
you. You were great. You're- This is me.
This is legal. And you were great.
Thank you very much. You're welcome.
I'm glad we could talk through this today. I'll stay available on day shift
if you need anything else. Have a good day.