Thank
you for bringing this forward, Michael. That sounds like a very serious safety concern.
And I'm sorry you and your colleagues are facing this dangerous situation.
Can you tell me the specific dates when this has been happening?
You mentioned two months. Do you remember when it started?
Sure thing. Yeah, I'd say it started pretty much from the day I got
on site, which was about two months ago.
So we're talking roughly early April. It's been the same situation since then.
Every day, same story, no harnesses. So yeah,
for about two months now, it's just been an accident waiting to happen.
I understand.
That's a long time to be working in unsafe conditions.
Can you tell me more specifically where this is happening?
You mentioned Construction Site North. What's the exact location or name of the site,
and which areas or departments are affected?
Absolutely. So we're at what they call the Northridge Expansion Site.
Kind of a mouthful, I know. Basically, it's the new wing they're adding on
the north side of the old facility, and the main area affected is all
the steel framework and roofing work. So anyone doing the high-level structural stuff,
that's where we're at. In other words, it's not just one little corner,
it's the whole elevated part of the project.
This is important information, Michael. So this affects everyone working on the steel framework
and roofing at the Northridge Expansion Site.
Can you tell me who else is involved? Who are the supervisors you've reported
this to? And are there other workers or witnesses who have seen these safety
issues? Absolutely.
And so the main supervisor I've reported this to is a guy named Dave.
Dave Henson. I've told him about it multiple times and so far no dice.
As for other folks, yeah, pretty much everyone up there working on those beams
and roof sections has seen it. We've all talked about it.
So it's not just me working waving a flag here.
There are a bunch of us who know it's a problem and have seen
the near misses.
Thank you for sharing this with me. It's clear this is affecting multiple workers,
not just you. You mentioned yesterday's near miss.
Can you tell me what exactly happened? I'd like to hear the details in
your own words about that incident and the ongoing safety issues.
Sure thing. So here's how it went down.
Yesterday, one of the guys was up there on the steel frame,
and he slipped. Lost his footing for just a second.
If he'd had a highness, no big deal. But he didn't.
He managed to catch himself on beam, but it was a really close hold.
And that's the kind of thing that could have been a full-blown accident.
And honestly, this isn't just a one-off. It's been the same risk day after
day. So that's the story in my own words. Just a close call that
really shouldn't have to happen.
I'm sorry you're all experiencing this.
That near miss sounds terrifying.
And you're absolutely right. It could have been much worse.
Given that this has been going on for two months with no response from
your supervisor, how urgent would you say this situation is?
Would you classify this as an immediate danger,
an ongoing problem, or a general concern?
Yeah.
I definitely call it an immediate danger. I mean,
when you're talking about working at heights with no fall protection,
that's not just a casual concern. It's an ongoing problem that's urgent,
because every day that goes by there's a real risk someone could get seriously
hurt or worse. So yeah, I'd say it's something that really needs attention right
away. Finally,
how can we contact
you if we need to
follow up?
You can provide a phone number or email,
or if you prefer // Your identity can remain anonymous.
Sure, you can go ahead and reach me by email.
I'm comfortable sharing that so you can follow up. Let's say it's mtempo at
example.com. And I appreciate you taking this seriously.
Let's hope we can get some harnesses up there and keep everyone safe.
Thanks for listening.
Thank you so much for reporting this, Michael.
Your courage in speaking up could prevent a serious accident.
resident, and protect your colleagues. I have all the information I need,
the immediate safety danger at Northridge expansion site,
the lack of fault protection equipment, and your contact details.
This will be escalated as an urgent safety matter.
Stay safe out there, and thank you for doing the right thing.
Absolutely, and thank you for helping get this on record.
Hopefully this gets things moving and makes the site safer for everyone.
Really appreciate the quick response. Stay safe,
and take care.
care for your colleagues.
Take care of yourself out there and thank you again for bringing this forward.
Absolutely, and thanks for the kind words. It's good to know it's in the
right hands now. I appreciate you hearing me out and handling it.
Take care and let's hope for a safer site soon.
Thank you, Michael. I'm confident this will get the attention it deserves.
Here's hoping those harnesses are on site very soon.
Take care, and stay safe until then.
Absolutely, and thanks for making Until
then, I'll stay safe as best I can. Thanks again and take care.
You've got it, Michael. Keep looking out,
for yourself and your team. Thanks for being so thorough and brave and reporting
this. All the best to you. Absolutely,
and thanks for guiding this through. Really appreciate the help.
I'll keep an eye out for any updates. All the best and thanks again.
Thank you very much. That was great.
I'm still not sure if it's captured it.
The last database didn't work. Well,
captured didn't work. But now it should hurt,
but it doesn't seem to So,
was that more easy to hear, this different browser approach?
Absolutely. That was much smoother in my end,
and it sounds like the browser switch did the trick. I'm glad we got-
We can possibly have to do one or two more of these,
because I'm not sure if this still